A Guide to the Auditor of Public Accounts Reports of Taxes Due on Dividends 1827-1869
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Reports of taxes due on dividends, 1827-1869
The Library of Virginia
APA 386
1 cf 2 volumes
Auditor of Public Accounts
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available.
Biographical Information
On 27 March 1843 the General Assembly imposed a tax upon the dividends paid by joint stock companies. The next day the General Assembly passed an act specifying the procedures to be followed in paying the tax, and requiring an officer of the company to report his company's dividends to the auditor of public accounts. The auditor kept accounts of the dividends and taxes due and issued warrants to the treasurer to receive the payments.
Scope and Content
Contains a list and register of joint stock companies within the state, letters with reports and amounts of taxes due or paid by joint stock companies, and two ledgers. The first ledger lists taxes on dividends paid by banks and insurance companies from 1861 to 1869. The second ledger lists taxes on dividends paid by banks and other businesses from 1843 to 1859.
The reports had to be "made on oath" by the Treasurer or another officer, a fact which several treasurer's were not aware of and belatedly sent reports in, such as the Staunton and James River Turnpike Company. Reports were often submitted annually or semiannually, although the conistency and frequency vary across the companies. Some companies list just the amount paid while others, like the Little River Turnpike Company's 1843 report, list the name and location of stockholders, the amount paid, and number of shares they hold in the company.
Arrangement
Documents are arranged numerically by folder title.
Contents List
- Commissioners of Revenue reports on joint stock companies paying dividends 1848-1850
  - Lists of Joint Stock Companies, 1827-1869 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Register of Joint Stock Companies, Stock Issued, and Dividends, 1827-1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 3 - Virginia Fire and Marine Insurance Companies, 1843-1851 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 4 - Chesterfield Railroad Company, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 5 - Portsmouth Savings Fund Society, 1843-1852 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 6 - Lynchburg Toll Bridge Company, 1844-1852 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 7 - Staunton and James River Turnpike Company, 1850-1851 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 8 - Tuckahoe and James River Railroad Comany, 1850-1851 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 9 - Fire and Marine Insurance Company Petersburg, 1844-1851 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 10 - James River Boat Company, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 13 - Mechanicsville Turnpike Company, 1844, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 14 - Brooke Turnpike Company, 1843, 1848, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 15 - French's Hotel Company, 1842-1851 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 16 - Virginia Towing Company, 1850-1852 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 16 - Winchester and Frederick County Savings Institution, 1843, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 17 - Ashby Gap Turnpike Company, 1844-1845, 1850-1851 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 20 - Lynchburg Manufacturing Company, 1844-1847, 1850, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 21 - Swiftrun Gap Turnpike Company, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 22 - White and Salt Sulphur Springs Turnpike Company, 1844, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 23 - Berryville Turnpike Company, 1844, 1849-1850 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 24 - Manchester Cotton and Woolen Manufacturing Company, 1844-1847, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 25 - Lynchburg and Campbell Court House Turnpike Company, 1844, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 26 - Hampton River and Mill Creek Toll Bridge Company, 1848-1851 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 27 - Louisa Railroad Company, 1843-1845 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 28 - Lafayette and English Ferry and Turnpike Company, 1844, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 29 - Petersburg Railroad Company, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 30 - Norfolk Draw Bridge Company, 1849-1852 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 31 - James River Manufacturing Company, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 32 - Lynchburg and Salem Turnpike Company, 1850-1852 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 33 - Virginia Woolen Factory, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 34 - Winchester and Potomac Railroad Company, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 35 - Little River Turnpike Company, 1843, 1848, 1850-1851 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 36 - Mechanic's Manufacturing Company, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 37 - Ettrick Manufacturing Company, 1850, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 38 - Merchants Manufacturing Company, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 39 - Battersea Manufacturing Company, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 40 - Washington and Alexandria Turnpike Company, 1850-1852 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 41 - Petersburg Aqueduct Company, 1850, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 42 - Warm Springs and Harrisonburg Turnpike Company, 1850, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 43 - Powell's Hotel Company (Petersburg), 1850-1852 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 44 - Valley Turnpike Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 45 - Clover Hill Railroad Company, 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 46 - Fire and Insurance Company of Alexandria, 1850-1852 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 47 - Fire and Marine Insurance Company (Wheeling), 1843, 1850-1852 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 48 - Wheeling Savings Institution, 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 49 - Western Insurance Company (Wheeling), 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 50 - Citizens Savings Bank (Lynchburg), 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 51 - Fredericksburg Aqueduct Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 53 - Fauquier White Sulphur Springs Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 54 - American Insurance Company, 1851-1852 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 55 - Belvidere Manufacturing Company, 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 56 - Midlothian Coal Mining Company, 1851-1852 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 57 - Belle Isle Manufacturing Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 58 - Harper's Ferry and Shenandoah Manufacturing Company, 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 59 - Leesburg Turnpike Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 60 - Little Kanawha Bridge Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 61 - Lynchburg and Concord Turnpike Company, 1850-1852 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 62 - Lynchburg and Blue Ridge Turnpike Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 63 - Mount Vernon Manufacturing Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 64 - Matoaca Manufacturing Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 65 - Pittsylvania and Lynchburg Turnpike Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 66 - Shepherdstown and Smithfield Turnpike Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 67 - Shannondale Springs Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 68 - Valley Telegraph Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 69 - Wheeling and Belmont Bridge Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 70 - Berryville and Charlestown Turnpike Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 71 - Exchange Hotel Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 72 - Smithfield, Charlestown, and Harper's Ferry Turnpike Company, 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 73 - Appomattox Railroad Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 74 - Warm Springs Mountain Turnpike Company, 1851-1852 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 75 - Lynchburg Hose and Fire Insurance Company, 1851-1852 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 76 - Kanawha Springs Institution, 1851-1853 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 77 - Fincastle and Blue Ridge Turnpike Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 78 - Indian Poll Draw-Bridge Company, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 79 - Red and Blue Sulphur Springs Turnpike Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 80 - Taylor Hotel Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 81 - Wythe Watering Company, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 82 - Norfolk Savings Institution, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 83 - Alexandria Savings Institution, 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 84 - Wytheville Savings Bank, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Wheeling Cotton Mills, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Wheeling Glass Company, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Ledger of Taxes on Dividends Paid by Banks and Insurance Companies, 1861-1869 (Book Ledger)
  - Ledger of Taxes on Dividends Paid by Banks and Other Businesses, 1843-1859 (Book Ledger)